待っていろ…！
I'm coming!
お前は…？
Who are you?
Party is over
But I still wanna dance
I can't even sleep
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
From the beginning I knew
One day the flames would die out
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
But even now, I'm so serious
Ah... I still have time to make it
Ah... but I'm gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling, it's not that easy
But surely it's not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
#11 The story of Banmon, part 1
Who are you? And those arms...
何者だ…その腕は
Hey, aren't you gonna thank us?
おいおい！礼のひとつも言えねえのかよ！
If it weren't for him, that samurai there
would be monster meat by now.
大体あにきがいなけりゃ、
そこの侍なんか今頃バケモンの腹ん中だぜ！
I know not who you are,
but thank you for saving him.
いずこの者かは知らぬが、助太刀…心より感謝する
Don't mention it.
へっへー。いいってことよ
The villagers can live in peace now.
これで村の者たちも安心して暮らせるだろう
What's wrong, bro?
どうした？あにき？
-He's blind so he sees with his soul.
-He's blind?
悪いな、あにきは目が見えない代わりに心の目で見るんだよ
目が？
He can fight like that
with no sight or arms?
目もなく、腕もなく、あれだけの立ち回りを…
That's how amazing he is.
そこがあにきのスゲーところさ！
He's beaten monsters left and right
traveling this land.
あっちこっちを旅しながらバッサバッサ！
And not some tiny little ghouls, either.
チンケなやつは相手にしねーよ。
We only go after the real deal,
demons and monsters.
狙うはとびっきりの強者！バケモン！鬼神どもって寸法さぁ！
So, pay up.
助け賃
Thanks.
フッ、まいど！
By the way, we heard there's
a rich province nearby. Know where it is?
ところでさ…ここらにえらく羽振りのいい国があるって聞いたんだけど、
知ってるか？
Must be our Lord Daigo's land.
ならば我が醍醐の国のことだろう
You'll reach the city limits
in half a day.
あと半日も下れば、城下の街へ入れる
Thanks. Let's go.
おぉー！ありがとな！行こうぜあに
Tell me your name.
お前…名は？
Hyakkimaru.
百鬼丸
Hyakkimaru...
百鬼丸…
Lord Daigo's land, huh?
我が醍醐の国、だってさ…
He was dressed well, so he might be
some important guy there.
いいモン着てたし、この国の偉いやつかもな
Hey come on, let's go.
おーい、あにき！行くぜー！
Forgive me, sir. I...
面目ない、若…俺は…
No, it is my fault for underestimating
that monster.
いや…責められるべきは、あの化け物の力を侮った私だ
I wouldn't lose to anybody in the dojo.
道場でならば、遅れをとるとは微塵も思わぬ。
But a real fight is a different matter.
だが本物の戦場に出れば…
That in itself is a futile argument.
先なき見立てでございます。
A vagabond and the heir to this land
cannot be compared.
一回の流れ者と、
この国を継がれる若とではそもそもお立場が違うのです
How about some fresh vegetables?
新鮮な野菜はいかがかね～？
They're all fine goods. Take a look.
どれもいい形でしょう。よかったら見てて！
A baby demon has been born, red all over
鬼の子生まれた真っ赤っ赤…
Should we feed it to the mountain beasts?
山の獣に食わしょうか…
Should we feed it to the ocean creatures?
海の魚に食わしょうか…
Wrap it up, send it adrift,
now it's out of sight
包んで流してもう見えぬ…
It's the demon! The demon child!
鬼じゃあ…！鬼の子じゃあ！
The demon child has come!
鬼の子が来たぁ…！
Look Hyakkimaru, rice balls!
And made with white rice, too.
あにき！握りメシがある！噂どおりの真っ白いメシだ！
And that, what is that?
それにあっちの…ありゃ何だ？
We'll need more than one day
to see all this.
こりゃ1日じゃ回りきれそうにないぜ！
Let's eat something first.
まずは…なんか食おうぜ！
Look, they're putting on a play
over there!
あにき！あっち芝居だってよ芝居！
For years on end,
さても長きにわたり、
demons have tortured our people.
我が醍醐の民を苦しめたはこの鬼神が仕業なり。
As the lord of this land
醍醐の主の名にかけて、
I, Daigo Kagemitsu,
shall now slay this demon!
この醍醐景光。いざ鬼神を退治てみせん！
Oh great Goddess of Mercy.
南無大悲市観世音菩薩
Please save Daigo's people
with your benevolence.
慈悲の光もて、醍醐の民を救いたまえ。
Do protect our lord.
我が殿を守りたまえ…
That guy's pretty awesome, huh.
すげーんだな。あのおっさん
"That guy"? How dare you!
おっさん？おっさんとは無礼な！
He's Lord Daigo Kagemitsu,
the man who made our land so rich.
あれはこの国を豊かにしてくださった、領主の景光様だぞ！
Well, you don't say.
ふぅーん。そりゃまるで…
He's just like you, bro.
あにきみてぇだなぁ。…ん？
The demon has been defeated!
鬼神は討ち果たしたり！
All foes who defy me will be vanquished.
逆らう敵はあまねく滅び、幾久しく末永く、
And my domain will be protected
for eternity!
あ醍醐の国は、守られた～り～！
I see.
I'm sorry for what happened to them.
そうかい…あの子たちには気の毒したねぇ
Did you come here
because of the rumors, too?
坊さんも…この町の噂を聞いてきたクチかい？
In a way.
まぁね。
This land is like none other
in these hard times.
このご時世にここだけ別天地じゃないか。
I was curious as to
what was blessing this country.
どんな御加護があってのことかと思ってねぇ
I heard the demons that Daigo defeated
are enshrined up there.
ここの領主が討ち果たした鬼神が祀られてるって話だ
I'm going up there to check on it.
ちょっくら見物してくるつもりさ
We got no business for
some long dead monsters.
とうに死んだバケモンなんか何にもならねえや。
We're only after the live ones,
the raging ones.
おいらたちが用があるのは、生きて暴れてる連中だ
Well, well.
そうかい…
Now then.
よっこらせっと
I see you've killed humans as well.
あんた…人を殺めたね？
You'd better be careful.
せいぜい気をつけな
You gotta be kidding me.
そいつは本当かい！
But dang.
まぁ…けど…
Maybe there's nothing for us to do here.
確かにここじゃおいらたちの仕事はなさそうだなぁ
Let's have a bit more fun here
and then go on to the next town.
もうちっと遊んだら、次の町行って儲け話でも探すかぁ。なぁ、あにき
Hey, bro?
って！あにき…？
I say it's the curse of Banmon.
ばんもんの祟りじゃねぇのかぁ？
I bet that's why it hasn't rained at all.
それのせいで、ここいらに雨が降らねぇってのかねぇ
Shh, you shouldn't say that.
しーっ！滅多なこと言うもんじゃねえ！
The villages I passed through
were all dry, too.
車で通った村も、さっぱり降らねぇってよぉ
If this continues, then this fall...
万一このまま続いたりしたら、今年の秋は…
What's wrong?
あにき？
Impossible. Lord Daigo's land
is protected by the Goddess of Mercy.
ありえねぇ！醍醐様のご領地は、観音様に守られてんだぞ？
Yeah, but ever since those things
started up at Banmon.
けどよぉ…ばんもんのあれが始まって以来だぜ？
Asakura's been acting suspicious, too.
朝倉の動きもきな臭いし…
Hey.
その！
What is that Banmon thing?
ばんもんってのは一体…何なんだい？
-What? A blind boy with no arms?
-Yes.
なにっ！？目も見えず、両腕もない男だと？
はい、
I believe one of his legs
is a prosthetic, too.
おそらくは片脚までも作り物かと。
They said they travel, defeating monsters.
化け物を倒しながら、諸国を旅しているとか
I would've died if he had not saved me.
助けてもらわねば…死んでおりました
They bragged that they were only after
strong demon gods.
狙うのは常に強い鬼神どもだと豪語しておりましたが、
And he really did slay a huge monster
with just one slash.
実際に巨大な化け物を一刀両断に切り裂いて…
His name is Hyakkimaru.
名は、百鬼丸と
It used to be a fort
that protected us from the Asakura clan.
元々は、朝倉の軍勢からこの国を守る砦だったのよ
There was a fierce battle,
and all except one wall got burned down.
激しい戦で、板塀1枚残して焼け落ちちまったが…
But that was the first time
Daigo's army drove the Asakuras away.
初めて醍醐の兵が朝倉の軍勢を退けた
Lord Kagemitsu's influence grew from here.
景光様のご威光も、ここから始まったんだ
Wow, what a tall wall.
ひぇ～っ！たっけぇ塀だなぁ
They say the Goddess of Mercy that
Lord Daigo's wife prays to dwells in it.
醍醐の奥方様の守り観音…その御加護が宿ってるってさ
But recently the Asakuras
have been getting stronger.
けどな、この頃は朝倉が盛り返してきてねぇ。
They shoot Daigo's men
and spies onto the wall.
捕らえた醍醐の兵や間者を打ち付けるのよ
They're trying to sully
the Goddess of Mercy's blessing.
観音様の御加護を穢そうってんだ。
Ghouls have been gathering nightly,
attracted to those corpses.
それに惹かれた化け物どもが夜な夜な集まり始めて、
Nobody goes near it now.
今はもう誰も近づかねぇ
Some say it might even be cursed
by the demons Lord Daigo defeated.
昔、景光様に打ち倒された鬼神の祟りもあるんじゃねぇかって…
Do you sense something?
あにき…なんか感じるかい？
A demon?
鬼神かい？
Very strong.
強い…かなり
Hey.
おい
Be careful.
If you cross that wall, you'll be killed.
気をつけろよ。それ以上向こうへ行くと…やられちまうぜ
Huh? You're just a kid.
Don't scare me like that.
なんだ！？子供じゃねーか。驚かしやがって！
See that? They're Asakura sentries.
見なよ。朝倉の見張りだ。
If they catch you,
they'll shoot you onto Banmon.
捕まったら最後、ばんもんに打ち付けられちまう
There's nothing to find here.
ここには何もないぜ。
Go rob corpses someplace else.
死体漁りなら、よそにしときな
That's not what we're here for.
We're going to beat Banmon's monster.
違わい！おいらたち、ばんもんのバケモンを退治に来たんだ
Monster?
えっ…バケモンを？
This used to be where our village was.
ここは元々、おいらたちの村だったんだ
They came barging in
and built that Banmon.
そこにいきなり…あのばんもんが立てられて…
My home is on the other side!
Let go, let go of me!
あっちに！おいらのうちがあるんだ！離せ！離せよ！
It's Asakura territory now.
You'll be killed!
あっち側はもう朝倉の陣地になっちまったんだ！殺されちまうぞ！
Papa... Mama... Mama...!
おとっつぁん！おっかぁ！おっかぁー！
Everyone abandoned the village.
みんな村を捨てて出て行った…
But I ain't giving up.
けどおいらは諦めねぇぞ！
I'll cross Banmon someday and get home.
必ずいつか…ばんもんを超えてうちに…
I'm going home!
帰るんだ！
-We'll help.
-Huh?
手伝う
-えっ？
So the Asakura army
keeps watch during the day.
昼は確かに朝倉の兵が見張ってる。
But what about night?
けど夜はどうなんだい？
Are you crazy? It's even worse at night.
馬鹿言え！夜はもっとやばいんだぞ？
You've never seen the likes of it.
お前ら見たことねえだろ！
-Huge monsters everywhere...
-Don't worry.
とんでもねえバケモンが、あそこら一面に…
大丈夫さ
My bro can handle that.
うちのあにきなら心配無用！
You meant it about beating the monsters?
本当なのか…バケモン退治に来たって
We usually don't do it for free.
ホントはタダ働きはしねえんだけどさ、
But you fed us, so it's a deal.
メシごちそうになったから負けといてやる。
I'm Dororo. This is Hyakkimaru.
おいらはどろろ！そっちは百鬼丸のあにき
I'm Sukeroku.
助六だ！
My son really is alive...
坊やが…本当に生きていた…
My lady, the lord is...
御方様、殿が
What are you going to do?
どうなさるおつもりですか？
I will not allow anybody
to interfere with my prosperity.
我が醍醐の反映を阻む者は、なんぴとたりとも許しはせぬ
-You think we should go unpunished?
-What?
許されることなのでしょうか
-なに？
Sacrificing the life
of an innocent child...
頑是ない子供の命を犠牲にして…
We will pay for what we did.
いずれ報いが来ます。
We may already be paying for it.
いえ、もしかしたら既に
You're saying I should've let
my land rot in hell as it was?
では奥は、あの頃のまま醍醐の国を地獄へ放っておけと申すのか
My lord, is it truly the well-being
of your people that you wish for?
殿…殿が望まれているのは、人々の幸せなのですか？
Or to defeat other domains
and become a great lord?
諸国に打ち勝ち、醍醐の名を天下に響かせるために…
For that, our son...
あの子の命を…
Women don't understand politics.
天下のこと、女にはわからん！
ASAKURA DOMAIN
-Daigo Kagemitsu did?
-He left an hour ago with a small troop.
醍醐景光はいっときほど前、わずかな兵のみで出かけたようで…
It didn't seem like a joyride,
and he wished to keep it secret.
夜遊びには物々しく、さりとておおごとにしたくないというような…
See? The Asakura sentries are leaving.
見な。麻倉の見張りも引き上げた。
It's almost time.
そろそろだぜ
So hey, Sukeroku. What's your mama like?
な…なぁ助六。お前の母ちゃんって、どんな…？
She's plump with white skin.
The prettiest in the village.
エヘッ！ぽちゃっとして、色が白くて、村一番のべっぴんだ！
-She makes the best rice cakes too.
-Yeah?
-ぼたもち作るのも、村一番うめえんだぞ！
-そっか
Once we meet her, you can have some too.
おっかぁと会えたら、お前らにもごちそうしてやっかんな！
Really? All right!
ホントか？やったぜ！
It's here.
来た！
It's a fox fire sprit.
狐火が…
That's the Banmon monster.
あれがばんもんのバケモンだ
There's more!
ぐっ！増えたぜ！
Wow, we really can win!
すっげぇ！これなら！
Look at all of them.
なんて数だよ…
It's called all the foxes around here.
ここら辺の狐が全部集まってきたんだ
Hyakkimaru! You stupid fox, take this!
あにき！このドギツネがこんちくしょう！これでも食らえ！
You jerk, you idiot! Take this, and this!
こんちくしょう！こんにゃろ！おととい来い！こんにゃろー！
Watch out...!
危っ…！
This is my chance...
今なら…
No, Sukeroku! It's dangerous to go alone.
おい！助六待って！1人じゃ…！
-Bro.
-Go.
-あにき！
-行け
Thanks.
すまねぇ！あにき
A demon.
鬼神…
Don't be rash, Sukeroku.
無茶すんじゃねぇぞ…助六
A traveling boy with a kid?
子供連れの旅の男ねぇ…
He's about my age or a bit older.
年の頃は私と同じか、少し上だが
Haven't seen him.
さて…
Hey, you haven't paid!
ちょ、ちょっと！お代！
-Young Master!
-Here.
-若…
-これで
He must still be around here somewhere.
おそらく、まだこの辺りに保留してると思うが、ですが…
But what are you going to do
if you find him?
あの流れ者を見つけたとして、どうなさるおつもりです
You said my father was shocked
when he heard your report.
お前たちの報告に、ひどく驚かれたと言ったな。
Father must know something about his past.
思い当たる節があるのだ。父上には、おそらく…
You mean...
それは？
Father and Mother's secret.
父上と母上の隠されているもの…
Where the baby disappeared to
16 years ago.
16年前に消えた赤子の行方…
That boy might have the answer
to all this.
私の知らない何かの答えを、あの男が持っているのだとしたら
A baby demon has been born, red all over
鬼の子生まれた真っ赤っ赤…
Should we feed it to the mountain beasts?
山の獣に食わしょうか…海の魚に食わしょうか…
-Hey, you there.
-Young Master, she's...
-おい、そこの女！
The demon child...!
お…鬼の子じゃあ…
The demon child has come back
to destroy Daigo!
鬼の子が…また醍醐を滅ぼしに戻ってきたあぁ…！
Sukeroku, Sukeroku!
助六ー！助六ー！
Where'd he go?
どこ行っちまったんだよ。
-Sukeroku!
-Hey, you!
-助六ー！
-おい貴様！
What are you doing there?
そこで何をしている！
Sukeroku...
助六…！
What do you mean by "demon child"?
鬼の子…とは一体何だ！
And "destroy Daigo"? What does that mean?
醍醐を滅ぼすとはどういう意味だ！
-Answer me!
-Young Master, do not listen to her.
答えろ！
-若、そのような者のたわごとを…
It's the curse of the demons!
鬼の祟りじゃあ～！
The demons ate the baby.
鬼が赤子を喰ろうたんじゃ…
Its arms, legs, nose,
mouth, skin, everything.
手も足も鼻も口も肌も全部…全部…
They ate everything!
全部…！
And now the child's come back
to return the curse to Daigo and his land!
醍醐の国に、祟りを返しに…帰ってきたんじゃあ…！
"HALL OF HELL"
This is very bad.
こいつは…まずいね…
Sorrow scatters in the wind,
piling up to form shadows
Our footsteps admonish
indifference in such verbose ways
As I peek into your fathomless eyes,
I lose my composure
Is there any hope
in the place I am heading to?
I feign amusement and laugh
because this road is so dark
I will be there to shine the light
I'm used to playing at saying goodbye,
but I cried when I waved to you
Our fiery woes fade... and fade...
until night falls upon us
If I knew tomorrow would be so mundane,
I wouldn't have said that I wanted to live
I know it's futile but can't help dreaming
of a future... a future... you are to blame
"Kyubi"